Hits You Like A Shot In The Heart.
The Spectacular Now is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by James Ponsoldt.
Sutter, a popular party animal, unexpectedly meets the
introverted Aimee after waking up on a stranger's lawn.
As Sutter deals with the problems in his life and Aimee plans for her future
beyond school, an unexpected romance blossoms between them.
Sutter Keely, played by Miles Teller.
Aimee Finecky, played by Shailene Woodley.
Ricky Mehlinger, played by Masam Holden.
Krystal Krittenbrink, played by Kaitlyn Dever.
Cassidy Roy, played by Brie Larson.
Tommy Keely, played by Kyle Chandler.
The Spectacular Now is a 2013 American coming-of-age romantic drama film directed by
James Ponsoldt, from a screenplay written by Scott Neustadter and Michael H.
Weber, based on the 2008 novel of the same name by Tim Tharp.
It stars Miles Teller and Shailene Woodley as high-schoolers Sutter and Aimee, whose
unexpected encounter leads to a romance blossoming between the two.
Brie Larson, Mary Elizabeth Winstead, Bob Odenkirk, Jennifer Jason
Leigh, and Kyle Chandler are featured in supporting roles.
The Spectacular Now premiered at the 2013 Sundance Film Festival, and was theatrically released in the United States
on August 2, 2013 where the film garnered critical acclaim, and grossed over $6 million worldwide.
It received two nominations at the 29th Independent Spirit Awards:
Best Female Lead (for Woodley) and Best Screenplay.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, alcoholism, coming
of age, high school student, based on young adult novel.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.